<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-16"?>
<data>

  <event start="1800" title="New sport played by Canadians ">
       Ice hockey, as we know it, is first played in either Nova Scotia, Windsor, Kingston, Ontario, or Quebec. Origin not clearly defined.
  </event>


  <event start="Feb 27 1877" title="First known rules published">
       On February 27th, 1877, the first known rules for hockey are published by the Montreal Gazette, a newspaper company.
  </event>
 
 
  <event start="1886" title="Amateur Hockey Association of Canada">
       The Amateur Hockey Association of Canada (AHAC) was the first notable ice hockey league organized in Canada, with four teams in Montreal, one in Ottawa and one in Quebec City.
  </event>      


  <event start="1893" title="Dominion Hockey Challenge Cup">
       Governer-General of Canada, Lord Stanley of Preston donates the Dominion of Hockey Challenge Cup (later named Stanley Cup) which is awarded to Canada's top-ranking amateur ice hockey club. First cup awarded to Montreal HC on 1893.
  </event>
       
       
  <event start="1915" title="Stanley Cup">
        In 1915, the two professional ice hockey organizations, the National Hockey Association (NHA) and the Pacific Coast Hockey Association (PCHA), reached an agreement in which their respective champions would face eachother for the newly renamed Stanley Cup.
  </event>
  
  
  <event start="1917" title="Suspension of NHA and formation of NHL">
        After unresolving issues within the organization, executives of three teams susped the NHA and form the NHL.
  </event>
  
  
  <event start="Nov 26 1917" title="First NHL teams announced">
        First five NHL teams announced to play in the first year of NHL. Teams included the Montreal Canadiens, Montreal Wanderers, Ottawa Senators, Toronto Arenas(Maple Leafs), and Quebec Bulldogs.
  </event>
  
  
  <event start="1924" title="Boston Bruins Join NHL">
       3rd team of the 'original six' dynasty formed - the Boston Bruins.
  </event>
  
  
  <event start="1926" title="Chicago Blackhawks Join NHL">
       4th team of the 'original six' dynasty formed - the Chicago Blackhawks.
  </event>
  
  
  <event start="1926" title="Detroit Red Wings Join NHL">
       5th team of the 'original six' dynasty formed - the Detroit Red Wings.
  </event>
  
  
  <event start="1926" title="New York Rangers Join NHL">
       6th team of the 'original six' dynasty formed - the New York Rangers.
  </event>
  
  
  <event start="1935" title="Montreal Canadiens avoid relocation">
       The Montreal Canadiens narrowly escape a relocation to Cleveland, Ohio, before a syndicate of Montreal bought the team. To this day, the Canadiens' team is one of the most notable teams in the NHL.
  </event>     
  
  
  <event start="1942" title="One of the Greatest Comebacks in the NHL">
       During the 1942 Stanley Cup Finals, The heavily favoured Toronto Maple Leafs were down 3-0 (in a best of 7 series) to the Detroit Red Wings. Toronto rebounded, and won 4 straight games to win the Stanley Cup to become the only team in history to win 4 straight games after trailing 0-3 in the Stanley Cup Finals. 
  </event>
  
  
  <event start="1945" ttle=" Maurice Richard and the 50-in-50 feat">
       Montreal Canadiens' Maurice Richard scores his 50th goal of the season on the fiftieth - and final - game of the season. Richard was the first of five players in NHL history to achieve this feat.
  </event>
  
  
  <event start="Mar 13 1948" title="Larry Kwong breaks NHL colour-barrier">
       On March 13th, 1948, Chinese-Canadian Larry Kwong(a.k.a the "China Clipper") plays his first game in the NHL and subsequently breaks the NHL colour-barrier of white players.
  </event>
  
  
 <event start="1952" title="CBC begins televising hockey games">
      Despite only 10% of Canadians owning a television set, the Canadian Broadcasting Corporation (CBC) began televising games.
 </event>
 
 
 <event start="Nov 1 1952" title="Hockey Night in Canada">
      Hockey Night in Canada first broadcasted on television, with broadcaster Foster Hewitt calling the action between the Toronto Maple Leafs and Boston Bruins. Hockey Night in Canada quickly became the highest-rated show on Canadian television.
 </event>
 
 
 <event start="Jan 18 1958" title="Willie O'Ree">
      On January 1st, 1958, Willi O'Ree Joined the Bruins as an injury callup. In doing so, becomes the first black player in the NHL.
 </event>
 
 
 <event start="May 2 1967" title="The End of a Dynasty">
    The end of the Original Six dynasty. The Toronto Maple Leafs beat the Montreal Canadiens, making it the start of the longest Stanley Cup drought in the NHL history, continuing on even today. 1967 was the last year the NHL consisted of only 6 teams.
 </event>
 
 
  <event start="October 1967" title="1967 NHL Expansion">
    The NHL undertook a major expansion for the 1967–68 season, adding six new franchises to double the size of the league: California Seals, Los Angeles Kings, Minnesota North Stars, Philadelphia Flyers, Pittsburgh Penguins, and the St. Louis Blues.
  </event>
  
  
  <event start="Jan 13 1968" title="Bill Masterson Death">
    On January 18th, 1968 Minnesota North Stars' rookie Bill Masterson died as a result of injuries caused by a forecheck, which landed him on his head. He was rushed to the hospital, and later passed away.
  </event>
  
  
  <event start="1970" title="NHL announces 2 new teams">
   The NHL announces the Buffalo Sabres and the Vancouver Canucks.
  </event>
  
  <event start="1971" title="Competition from the World Hockey Association">
   The NHL faced competition from the newly formed World Hockey Association in 1972. The WHA lured many skilled players from the NHL by offering grand contracts to them.
  </event>
  
  
  <event start="1972" title="NHL expands to 16 teams">
   The threat of the WHA caused the NHL announce the creation of the New York Islanders and the Atlanta Flames.
   </event>
   
   
   <event start="1973" title="NHL expands to 18 teams">
    The year following the 1972 expansion, the NHL announces two more teams: the Kansas City Scouts and the Washington Capitals.
   </event>
   
   
   <event start="1976" title="Franchise relocations">
    After 40 years of existence, the NHL approved franchise relocations. The Kansas City Scouts moved to Denver, becoming the Colorado Rockies. The California Golden Seals became the Cleveleand Barons. Just two years later, the Barons merged with the North Stars reducing the NHL to 17 teams.
   </event>
   
   
   <event start="1978" title="WHA and NHL merger">
    Following the 1978-1979 season, the WHA folded and six WHA teams joined the NHL:The Edmonton Oilers, Hartford Whalers, Quebec Nordiques and Winnipeg Jets joined the NHL as expansion teams.
   </event>
 
  
  <event start="1980" title="Atlanta Flames move to Alberta">
   The 1979-80 season was the last for the Atlanta Flames. Due to lack of attendance and failure to produce revenue, the Atlanta Flames were sold for $16 million, and relocated north to become the Calgary Flames in 1980-81.
  </event>
  
  
  <event start="1981" title="Wayne Gretzky Reaches Unbreakable Record">
   During the 1981-1982 season, Wayne Gretzky, named the best hockey player in the world, reached a record breaking total of 92 goals and 120 assists, combining a sum of 212 points. Four years later, Gretzky beats his own record by earning 215 points.
  </event>
  
  
  <event start="1982" title="Colorado Rockies move to New Jersey">
  In the 1982-83 season, the Colorado Rockies were sold for $30 million, and left Denver to become the New Jersey Devils.
  </event>
  
  
  <event start="Aug 9 1988" title="Wayne Gretzky Traded to Los Angeles Kings">
   After money issues with the owener of the Oilers, Wayne Gretzky was traded to the Los Angeles Kings.
   </event>
   
   
   <event start="1991" title="NHL expands to three more teams">
   During the 1991-1992 season three new teams joined the NHL: San Jose Sharks, Ottawa Senators, Tampa Bay Lightning.
   </event>
   
   
   <event start="1993" title="NHL adds two more teams">
    Two teams added in the NHL: Florida Panthers and Mighty Ducks of Anaheim. Minnesota North Stars also change to Dallas Stars.
    </event>
    
    
    <event start="1995" title="Relocation of Quebec Nordiques">
    In 1995, the Quebec Nordiques relocate to Denver to become the Colorado Avalanche.
    </event>
    
    
    <event start="1996" title="Relocation of Winnipeg Jets">
    The Winnipeg Jets relocate to Arizona to become the Phoenix Coyotes.
    </event>
    
    
    <event start="1997" title="Relocation of Hartfort Whalers">
    The Hartfort Whalers relocate to Carolina to become the Carolina Hurricanes.
    </event>
    
    <event start="1998" title="Nashville Joins NHL">
    In 1998, the NHL expands and creates one more team - the Nashville Predators.
    </event>
    
    
    <event start="1998" title="NHL Allows Players Play in Olympics">
    To further market their players, the NHL decided to allow NHL players to play in the Olympics, starting in the 1998 Nagano Games in Japan.
    </event>

    
    <event start="1999" title="Atlanta Joins NHL">
    In 1999, NHL expands to Atlanta by adding the Atlanta Thrashers.
    </event>
    
    
    <event start="2000" title="NHL Expands by Adding 2 teams">
    In 2000, the league added two franchises, boosting the total number to 30. The NHL returned to Minnesota with the Minnesota Wild and added the Columbus Blue Jackets in Columbus, Ohio.
    </event>
    
    
    <event start="Nov 22 2003" title="NHL First Outdoor Game">
    In 2003, the Edmonton Oilers hosted the very first NHL outdoor game against the Montreal Canadiens. MON 4:3 EDM
    </event>
    
    
    <event start="2005" title="NHL Suffers 2004-2005 Lockout">
    Due to disagreements between the players and NHL management, A full-year lockout caused the cancellation of the entire 2004-2005 season.
    </event>
    
    
    <event start="2005" title="NHL Removes Tie Games, Adds Shootout">
    In the 2005–06 season, the NHL eliminated tie games, as the shootout was introduced to decide all regular season games tied after the five-minute overtime period.
    </event>
    
    
    <event start="2005" title="Alexander Ovechkin and Sidney Crosby join NHL">
    In the 2005–06 season, rookies Alexander Ovechkin and Sidney Crosby began their careers. In their first three seasons, they each won both the Art Ross and Hart trophies; Crosby in 2007,[149] and Ovechkin in 2008.
    </event>
    
    
    <event start="2009" title="Phoenix Coyotes File for Bankruptcy">
    Due to financial troubles, the Phoenix Coyotes file for bakcruptcy in May 2009. The NHL eventually took control over the team, with the hopes of eventually reselling it to a new owner who would be committed to stay in the Phoenix market.
    </event>
    
    
    <event start="2011" title="Atlanta Thrashers relocate to Winnipeg">
    The financially struggling Atlanta Thrashers were sold and then relocated to Manitoba to become the Winnipeg Jets.
    </event>

  
   <event start="2012" title="NHL Enters Second Lockout in 21st Century">
   he NHL again entered lockout in 2012, cancelling the first 526 games, about 43% of the season, until at least December 30, 2012. Just after 5 am on January 6, 2013, after approximately 16 continuous hours of negotiating, the NHL and the player's union reached a deal on a new agreement to end the lockout.
   </event>
  
</data>


