<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-16"?>
<data>

<event start="Oct 27 2009" title="League of Legends Launch">
League of Legends officially gets launched in both North America and Europe</event>

<event start="Mar 30 2010" title="Twisted Treeline map released">
The highly anticipated Twisted Treeline map is launched.</event>

<event start="July 12, 2010" title="Season One Launch">
The first competitive season is announced for League of Legends. Along with the competitive scene, new features are included in the launch (ranked games,draft mode, ranking ladders).</event>


<event start="November 3, 2010" title="Battle Training">
The new system called "Battle Training" is realeased. This system teaches new players on the basics of the game.</event>


<event start="December 14, 2010" title="Automated Leaver Banning">
League of Legends introduces the latest addition to Leaver Buster: Automated Leaver. This software automatically bans players who leave.</event>


<event start="January 19, 2011" title="AFK Detection">
The LeaverBuster system is now able to detect players who are AFK (Away From Keyboard). Once detected, the player is kicked out of the game.</event>


<event start="February 15, 2011" title="Co-Op versus AI">
The new game mode "Co-Op versus AI" allows new players to play together against AI. This helps players understand the game much more, while having fun at the same time.</event>


<event start="May 24,2011" title="Tribinual is Launched">
The Tribinual allows players from the community to become much like a court room, reported players are sent to the tribinual and there a group of people decide whether the person is worthy of a punishment or not.</event>


<event start="June 18,2011" title="Season One Championships">
The long awaited competitive scene for League of Lengends is played on June 18, 2011 at DreamHack in Jönköping, Sweden. With the biggest prize pool of eSports ,$100,000 and a grand prize of $50,000, teams eagerly raced to first place. The Winner was Fnatic MSI.</event>


<event start="September 13, 2011" title="End of Season One">
The first season of League of Legends comes sto an end.</event>


<event start="September 26, 2011" title="League of Legends Dominion">
The new game mode, Dominion, is released. The new game mode is a much like capture the flag, with 5 flags that can be captured by both teams, in the end, whichever team has the most points, wins. </event>


<event start=November 22, 2011" title="Season Two Launch">
Much like Season One, Season Two is released, New competitive scene, new teams, new content.</event>


<event start="December 12, 2011" title="Korean Server Launch">
With the huge amount of players in Korea, a server fully dedicated for Korea is launched.</event>


<event start="April 27,2012" title="Spectator mode full release">
Spectator mode is released, this feature allows players to spectate their friend's games.</event>

<event start="June 2,2012" title="Romania, Greece, Brazil, and Turkey server launch">
With the avid amount of players in Romania, Greece, Brazil, and Turkey a server is released in each country.</event>


<event start="October 1, 2012" title="Honor Initiative">
Once you have finished a game, you may honor players for their Teamwork, Friendlyness, Honorable Opponent, or Helpful Team mate.</event>


<event start="October 13, 2012" title="Season 2 Championships">
The Season 2 championships for the competitive scene is held on this day at the Galen Center. This championship had the biggest prize pool of $2,000,000.</event>


<event start="November 12, 2012" title="End of Season Two">
Season Two officialy comes to and end. Players who achived certain rankings, were rewarded with in-game prizes.</event>


<event start="February 1, 2013" title="Season Three Launch">
Much like Season One, and Season Two, Season Three is released with a new competitive scene, new teams, and new content</event>


<event start="March 23, 2013" title="Italy, Russia, CIS, Latam, and Oceania Server Launch">
With the huge fanbase in Italy, Russia, CIS, Latam, and Oceania a server is released in these countires.</event>

<event start="October 4, 2013" title="Season Three World Championships">
The biggest gaming event ever held in the world takes place at The Staples Center in Los Angles, with yet another prize pool of $2,000,000.</event>


<event start="November 12, 2013" title="End of Season Three">
Season Three officialy comes to and end. Players who achived certain rankings, were rewarded with in-game prizes.</event>


<event start="January 14, 2014" title="Season 4 Launch">
Much like Season One, Season Two, and Season Three, Season 4 is released with a new competitive scene, new teams, and new content</event>


</data>
